Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpurohit, I am the founder
of Family Fund Financial Services, I have an MBA in Finance and have been working in the corporate sector for 14 years and
today I am presenting to you about the
best selling Term Plus ULIP in India in January 2025
, about Term Life Insurance of Tulip category, in recent times there has been innovation in many insurance products,
out of which this is a big innovation where the customer
is getting the benefit of term insurance as well as investment because before this
it was heard from most of the people that purchase a pure term plan separately and
invest separately in mutual funds, this type of feedback
was also going to the insurance company, so the insurance company also innovated in its product
and keeping in mind the needs of the customer, they
are also giving the benefit of investment, also giving a big benefit of term insurance, plus
giving tax benefits, so today we will compare India's top term insurance in this video Five
company Tally policies in which first will be
Protect and Gain Life of ICICI Potential Life Insurance,
Param Raksha of Tata Life Insurance which has four variants,
Smart Protect Plan of HDFC Life Insurance, Invest Protect Goal 3 of Bajaj Allianz Life Insurance
which was relaunched recently and Tulip Policies of Kotak Life Insurance.
What are the features of these five plans, what are the benefits, what are the riders, what is the premium,
we will understand all of them in details and also understand whether pure term plan
will be better for you or the one with Tally policy, will Term Plus SIP still
be better for you or these Tally policies, let us understand all the benefits and features in details. If you
like this video, then you
will find more than 2 videos of my insurance on YouTube which
will help you in your financial planning and first of all let me tell you one more thing, if you
go to purchase these five plans online also, then there is no dire need, whether you purchase from an advisor or purchase online
or purchase from the company's website, you will get it at the same premium, so I would suggest
that you Purchase from an advisor because they will help you in better fund selection and
provide after sales service. Now when you go to purchase a policy,
many times people will tell you that a term plus ULIP plan
will be more expensive than a pure term plan, but this does not happen every time. Let us understand this with an example. Max Life Insurance
has just launched a pure term plan in January 2025, named Smart
Term Plan Plus. This is a pure risk insurance cover where a 45-year-old
person who is purchasing the policy is a male and a non-smoker and he
is taking an insurance cover of 50 lakhs for 12 years. He will pay the premium in it. He
is taking a policy term of 40 years and in pure risk cover, he is taking a cover of 50 lakhs. Now you will see here that
his premium is coming to 5368, in which GST
will be applicable on 18 and after GST on 18,
the amount you will have to pay from your pocket every year will be
6260. What will be your benefit in this? There will be a cover of 50 lakhs for
the family in case of any death. If you survive, there is no maturity benefit.
Even if you die in an accident, you will get 50 lakhs. If you become disabled, there is no benefit and
you will not get any maturity benefit. But along with this, let us
understand another example in which suppose you are purchasing a policy, Sampoorna Raksha Promise,
that too is a pure risk policy where a 45-year-old person is taking the policy,
paying premium for 12 years, he is purchasing a pure risk cover of 50 lakhs
and for that, his premium in the first year is
9136, after GST it will be
9780, that means you have to pay approximately 0000 for 12 years. If there is a natural death, you
will get 50 lakhs. Even if there is an accidental death, you will get 50 lakhs. If you become disabled, you will not
get anything and if you survive, you will not get anything because there
is no maturity benefit in it. But if you buy term instead of pure term You purchase a Tally policy,
you purchase a Term Plus Uly policy, if a 45 year old person purchases this policy
and pays the premium for 12 years, then with GST,
the premium here will be Rs. 64,000, without GST, the premium here is Rs. 61,000, the GST levied here
is only on the rider's premium, here the rider's premium
is quite less, so GST of around Rs. 3,000 will be charged, for the rest
Rs. 619.60 you have to pay the premium for 12 years, the policy will run for 40 years,
it will run till 2065, if you purchase it in 20225, you
will see that you are also getting a natural cover of Rs.50 lakh
You are getting an accidental cover of Rs. 50 lakhs and a disability cover of Rs. 50 lakhs
and the premium is also low, it is less than Rs. 70,000, 000 plus if you survive,
you get a maturity of Rs. 7332,7332000 and that percentage. If the fund performs better than this
, you can get a higher maturity, plus parcel withdrawal and many other
facilities are also available, meaning at the same premium, even at a lower premium, you
are getting maturity, additional benefit of accidental and
disability cover is also available. So it is not necessary that
purchasing a pure term plan is cheaper every time.
Now let us understand SIP plus pure term plan versus Tulip policy. Term plus
Tulip policy. First of all, let us understand SIP and Tulip. Suppose there
are two friends, both of them are of the same age. One person does a SIP of Rs. 00 per month and the other
purchases a Tulip policy. If unfortunately both of them die,
how much money will go to the family of one friend of one family? 10000 vs 11000, 12000, 15000
maximum. But how much money will go to the other friend's family? One crore rupees because
in that premium, he could have easily got a 1 crore policy for 00 monthly premium
and that too in a limited 10-12 year premium payment period. Suppose both of them do not die.
Suppose both of them get disabled in an accident. Then
how much money will go to the family of the SIP friend? Nothing, whereas in the policy with term plus ULIP, one crore
will go because there is also disability benefit and if both of
them survive, they will also get maturity as per the market returns. They
will also get maturity as per the market returns. But
in the Tulip one, you will get tax free maturity whereas in SIP you will also have to pay long term capital gains
tax. One customer takes SIP as well as pure term plan
and the other friend only takes 1 crore. When you purchase a policy, first of all you
see that pure term plan is not as cheap as Tulip
or even if it is cheaper somewhere, then the premium of SIP will also be there,
they will have to pay an installment, secondly the underwriting guidelines for taking a pure term plan
are very strict, most of the insurance companies that
offer pure term plan ask for your education to be a graduate, in which you
must be either a salaried person or a businessman, thirdly you get a pure term plan only if your income is 5 lakhs or more,
but this Tulip policy,
in it you get it even if your income is less than 5 lakhs, you get
it even if you are 5th pass, whereas not everyone gets a pure term plan, thirdly suppose you
have purchased a pure term plan and SIP, there you do not get liquidity, there
is no option of partial withdrawal, but you get the facility to withdraw money after five years in Tulip policy,
after withdrawing money there is parcel withdrawal Even after doing this
, your insurance cover is still running whereas if the pure term plan
was in SIP, then nothing like this would happen. There, in a pure term plan, you
will have to pay the premium otherwise the policy will be closed but in Tulip policies, if
even minimum two or three premiums are paid, then your insurance cover continues, that too
is a good benefit. Third, if you go for a pure term policy, if you are a smoker, then
an extra premium of up to 75 per cent is charged on the smoker but this is also one such plan among the five products
where the same premium will be charged on the smoker as
is charged for the non-smoker, so there are many different criteria, you can understand according to your need
which of these five is best for you. Talking about the premium payment term
, in ICICI's Protect and Gain Life, you will also get the option of paying regular premium. You
will get the option of premium payment of five years, six years, seven years, eight years, 10 years, 12 years.
In Tye Life Insurance, you will also get the option of regular premium from plus
five to K. You can select any premium payment term between
5, 6, 7, 8, 10, 12, 15, 25, 35, whichever premium payment term you wish to select,
you can do so. In ADFC Life Insurance, you
will get the option of Regular premium payment term plus only 10, 11 and 12. Only three options are given in Limited Pay
. This has changed recently in ADFC.
In Bajaj's Invest Protect Goal, you will get the option of Regular Pay plus there is also an option of 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11
and 12 will also be available. And in Quota's Tally policy, you
can pay regular premium as well and options of 6, 7, 8, 9, 10 and 12 are given here.
Talking about the policy term, the maximum policy term in all except TA is 40 years.
You can take a policy term of 82 in Tata, which means
a person of 18 years can purchase a policy up to 100 years.
If we talk about the policy term in ICICI, the minimum policy term is 30 years and the maximum policy term is 40 years. In Tata,
the minimum policy term is 30 years and the maximum is 82 years. In HDFC,
you can take a minimum policy term of 25 years, the maximum is 40 years. In Bajaj, the minimum
policy term is 20 years, the maximum is 40 years and in Kotak, you can take a minimum policy term of 30 years,
the maximum policy term will be 40 years. If we talk about A Entry Judge,
a person from 18 to 60 years can purchase this policy. In ICICI,
a person from 18 to 50 years can purchase this policy because if
we look at the maturity age also, in all other plans, you can take a policy up to 100 years, which means a person
of 60 years can purchase the policy. If you purchase the policy at any age, you can run it till 100 years, but
the maximum maturity age in ICICI will be 90. Because the entry age is 50, so if
we make 50 or 40, then your policy can mature at the age of 90. What is the minimum
sum you will get from this insurance? So the minimum sum of IIT & T
will start from 50 lakhs. In ADFC Life, in most of the channels, it is available from 50 lakhs,
but in some channels, you can take it even from 25 lakhs if you wish.
In Kotak and Bajaj Allianz Insurance, it depends on the multiplier. Here,
you can take a minimum of seven times the annual premium, 10 times or 15 times.
So, you can take it for 50 lakhs or even less than 25 lakhs. If
you wish to convert it like a ULIP, you can do that. If you wish to take it like a term plus ULIP,
you can take it in the policy. The maximum sum here is any There is no limit in the policy
, which means you can take 1 crore, 5 crore or even 50 crore. If your on paper
income is that much, then you can take the biggest cover
in any of these five plans. Talking about accidental rider benefit,
all the policies have accidental death benefit rider, so the minimum rider, if
we talk about accidental death benefit, the minimum rider sum
will be 50 lakh in ICICI and HDFC, ICICI Tata will be 25 lakh in HDFC and
in Bajaj and Kotak, you can take accidental cover around the base sum you have taken.
The maximum accidental cover you can take is up to 3 crore in ICICI.
In Tata, you can take maximum accidental death benefit rider up to 5 crore.
In HDFC, you can take a rider of only 1 crore. Suppose you
have taken a pure term plan of 5 crore, even then you will be able to take accidental rider of only 1 crore in Bajaj.
You can take a rider up to Rs. 5 crore and in Kotak this rider
is available for a maximum of Rs. 50 lakh only. Even if you have taken a policy of Rs. 1 crore, you
can take a rider in it for a maximum of Rs. 50 lakh only. Accidental Total and Permanent Disabilities Minimum Sum and you
can take Rs. 50 lakh in Tata ICICI. In Bajaj you
can take as much as the minimum base sum you take because you can get cover for that less also and in ADFC you
can take Rs. 25 lakh maximum. The maximum you can take is Accidental and Total Disabilities rider,
in ICICI you can take Rs. 3 crore. In Tata you can take Rs. 5 crore. In ADA you
can take a maximum of Rs. 2 crore only. In Bajaj you can
take a rider for disabilities for a maximum of Rs. 3 crore. And in Kotak’s Tali policies
there is no Accidental Total and Permanent Disability rider. There it is mandatory that you will have to take Critical Illness cover,
this Accidental Death and Accidental Total and Permanent Disabilities
are mandatory riders, you have to take them, you cannot remove them, but in Kotak
there is accidental death benefit rider, there is no disability rider, but
there is a critical illness rider, you will have to take it mandatory, so this
is a Tulip policy, if we talk about critical illness benefit, then
you will get the critical illness benefit rider in ADFC, which is optional, if you want to add it
as extra then you can do it, if you don't want to, then it is up to you, but in Kotak
you will have to take it mandatory, cancer cover separately, if you want to take only cancer cover,
then optional benefit is available in ADFC, you can take it, now because
this is a Tulip policy, there are charges in ULIP, so
in Tulip policy, because you are taking a bigger cover, then the charges will also be a little bigger, but the good
thing is that whatever charges are deducted in it, you get a refund, for example,
purchase ICICI's Protect and Gain Live policy, by the way I to tell you
Let me tell you that suppose you are taking premium payment for 12 years, then premium
allocation charges are not charged for 12 years, it is charged only for four to five years in most of the company's
plans. So if you have taken ICICI's Protect and Gain Life Option, then
whatever premium allocation charges deducted from your 11th year, you will get back double of that.
In HDFC also you will get back double of that. Sorry
in Tata you will get back double of that from 11th year. In HDFC also you will get back double of that. In Bajaj's
Invest Product Goal, you will get back all the allocation
charges deducted for 15 years together. And in Kota's Tally Policy you
will get double of that. From the 2nd year of the policy onward, you will get double of that after 10 years.
Regarding mortality
charges, because you are taking a big insurance cover, then there
will be mortality charge in that. There will be insurance charge. You will get that too in ICICI. You get double return
from 11 years and four times return from 26 years. In Tata, you get double return through
policy term from 11 years. In HDFC Life Insurance, you get double return
from 11 years and three times return from 25 years. And in Bajaj's Invest Protect Goal,
you get the bulk of the mortality charges back in the seventh year, the amount
of mortality charges deducted from the first to the seventh year, at 25%. Then you get the charges back in 15 years.
Whatever mortality charges deducted from the first year to 15 years, that minus what
was given to you earlier, will be deducted in the seventh year. In the same way,
if you go to the 20th year also, then you will get the total mortality charges deducted from one year to 20 years,
that entire amount minus what was given to you earlier, in the same way it
will remain in the rest of the policy term as well. Talking about the refund of
mortality charges in Kotak's Tali policy, first of all, the charges that you get during the policy term of 11 to 20 years
will start. The amount deducted in the policy will be refunded once. If we talk about 20 to 30,
you will get double and between 31 to 40, you
will get three times the mortality charges refund. Refund of FMC charges, fund management charges.
Even in mutual funds, the fund manager does not refund his fees, but
in HDFC Life Insurance's Smart Protect plan, if your fund manager's fees, which are FMC
charges, are also
refunded at the end of the policy, at the time of maturity of the policy, you do not get this in any leaf of any company, neither do you get it
in SIP or mutual fund, the fund manager refunds his fees after a few days, but
in this plan you also have this benefit. Talking about maturity booster,
in ICICI Provincial, on maturity,
you will get maturity booster up to 20% of the average fund value of the last 3 years, suppose the average fund value is
₹ 40 crore, then % 20 lakh of 1 crore will be available as maturity booster.
Maturity booster is available in AI's Param Raksha Life Plus as well as in its other four variants.
To know under which conditions you
can whatsapp me. There is no maturity booster in the plan. There is loyalty addition. As you
saw that ICICI is giving maturity booster to itself, SDFC
is refunding its fund management charges, Tata is also giving maturity booster
with term and condition. But these three benefits are
not being provided by Kotak and Bajaj Ace. But both of them are giving you loyalty addition. Like
in Bajaj Ella Life Insurance, whatever your average fund value will be for every two years,
at that time its amount will be added to your fund value. At 20 years 2, it will be added to your fund value. At
30 years 4, it will be added to your fund value. Sorry, at 30 years 3
, and at 40 years 5, you will get this loyalty addition in your fund value. And
if we talk about Kotak, in Kotak, if you keep the premium payment term for the policy less than 10 years, then the amount will be credited to your fund value. If the term
is between 30 to 40, then you
get the average fund value of the last 3 years at 14 per cent. But if your premium payment term was 10 years or more, suppose the policy
term is 40 years, then you get loyalty benefit up to 30 per cent. And even if you
are taking the policy in regular pay, suppose the policy term is 4 years and the premium payment
term is 40 years, then you get loyalty addition up to 26 per
cent. Talking about terminal benefit, terminal benefit means that a disease
occurs which is not possible to be cured, and the doctor is giving in writing that
the customer may die within 6 months, then
in the four variants of this Param Raksha of Tata, this option is available in three out of four variants that you get terminal benefit.
Terminal illness cover will be available 10% per
your sum. Suppose you have an insurance cover of one crore, then if
you get a terminal illness, you will get ₹ lakh of it, the rest will be given on death and
even after death, you will get the fun value or sum which ever is higher.
This option of terminal illness is not available with the rest of the three and four companies.
In these coolie policies, let's talk about how much total fund you will get for investing
because these are coolie policies, here you
get funds to invest and you also get a strategy. So here in ICICI
you have about 25 funds where you can invest, there are equity funds, there
are balance funds, if you want to invest in debt funds, you can do that. If you want
to switch from one fund to another, you can do that. In ADFC Life, you
will get nine funds. In TA, you will get 22 funds. In Bajaj Allianz, 18 funds are available in this plan
and you will also get nine funds in Kotak and along with this, in these plans
you will get Automatic strategy is also given that if you are not able to manage the fund or you
do not want to do it, then there is edge based strategy or ATP type, every month your
investment is made in debt to equity, you can also select this type of strategy,
if you take my suggestion, then you should always choose the fund which
is your risk taking ability, suppose you want to take 100% risk, you
can invest up to 100% in equity, you can also invest in debt fund, you can also invest in balanced fund,
so you can also select the fund as per your choice, once you
select the fund, after that your fund manager will manage the liquidity, if
you need money, then after 5 years in all these plans you
are given the option of liquidity, the option of partial withdrawal is given in which
in ICICI Prudential you can do partial withdrawal of 20 of your fund value
after 5 years in TA Life Insurance if you have taken regular premium policy or
limited premium policy So except for two premiums,
you can take the rest of the fund value as partial withdrawal. If you
have taken a single premium policy, then you can keep 10% of the single premium amount with the company and
take the rest of the fund value as partial withdrawal. Talking about HDFC Life
Insurance, you can also do partial withdrawal in HDFC Life Insurance.
As long as at least two premiums remain in the policy, your insurance cover
will continue. Talking about Bajaj Invest Protect Goal 3,
as long as three annual premiums remain in the policy, your insurance cover will continue.
In this also, benefits of partial withdrawal are given.
I will try to explain it to you with an example. Suppose you select a premium payment term of 10 years.
Select a policy term of 40 years. Suppose your insurance cover is of crores. Now,
for example, the premium is ₹1 lakh. In 10 years, you have paid ₹1 lakh and
suppose your fund value becomes ₹1 lakh. So, how much should be the three annual premiums? If you lose ₹ lakh, then
as long as you are in the account, ₹ lakh will remain with Bajaj.
You can take the remaining 12 lakh as partial withdrawal. If you want, you can take 12 lakh or 2 lakh as well.
You can take it as per your requirement. But this facility is available but as long as
three premiums remain in the account, your insurance cover will continue. Now, if
you do partial withdrawal of this insurance, the insurance cover will reduce. Yes,
it is like this in all these policies. For example, suppose you
had an insurance cover of one crore and you do partial withdrawal of ₹ lakh, then your death benefit will now be 8 lakh. But
this insurance cover of 8 lakh will remain for the next 24 months. As soon as 24 months
are completed, your insurance cover will again become one crore.
If we talk about Kotak's Tulip policy in five policies, then here, whatever
total premium you have paid at 50%, keep 50% of it inside and you can take the remaining money
as partial withdrawal. But if you want to take it, you can take it. This is a facility, it is not like that
as soon as the fifth year is completed you start taking money. This is a facility,
take it only if you need it, otherwise keep it in the policy, you
will get growth in it as per the fund performance and on investment up to ₹ lakh, the growth that comes on it
will be tax free. Now let's talk about online discount. Online discount
is not available in these 500 policies. What most people do is they call an agent to their home,
understand the policy in full detail and then go online to compare the same policies and
purchase it from there, but there is no facility of this kind in this plan that
You call the agent and after understanding it, go online and purchase the policy. Whether
you purchase it online or from an agent, you will get this policy at the same premium. So
the suggestion would be to purchase it from an agent. First, he will provide you service, which fund
is performing well, what is the fund value, will also keep giving you information from time to time,
can help you in switching in case of good fund performance.
There are many other benefits when you look at the policy, fund of fund etc. and policy servicing, or even the
claim because the insurance cover in this is 1 crore, then
it will also help your family in the claim, the premium is going to be the same.
Give preference to the advisor. Talking about Systematic Withdrawal Plan, here
you will get the option of SWP in III, Tata and rest, the option of SWP is not available in ADAC, Bajaj and Kotak.
You will get the benefit of switching in all the five policies, where you
can switch from one fund to another according to your need,
for example. But even now in January the market
is a little down. If you want to go to the safe side or go to the dip fund, you can go.
The market crashed a lot during the Covid time, but in this policy you
do not need to exit anywhere. You
can switch from one fund to another in the same policy while sitting at home. This is an excellent facility which is probably
not available in mutual funds etc. Let us also talk about premium redirection. Suppose you
have invested in a fund now and next year when you want to pay the premium, you want to invest in another fund.
Then you can also redirect that fund.
You will get this facility
. At the time of third benefit, if you do not want to take a lump sum amount but
want to take it as income every year for a few years, then you can select this option. Talking about death benefit,
in all five policies, the death benefit will be your sum assured or fund value, whichever is
higher, you will get it. Let us talk about it because again I say that
there is also a portion of investment in it. So here you There are many funds available
for investment ranging from nine to 22 funds. If we talk about their fund performance
, if I talk about the average of last 5 years, then ICICI's Value Nasr Fund
has given a return of 16.8%. Tata A's Top 200 Fund has given
a return of 27.9% in the last 5 years. STFC Life's Protect Smart
Protect Plan has given you a return of 25.6% in Discovery Fund. In Bajaj, you have got
a return of 17.8% in Accelerated Milk Fund 2 in the last 5 years and in Kotak,
you have got a return of 1% in Front Line Equity Fund. This fund has
given such a return in the last 5 years. The performance of most of the funds of all the companies
is quite good since last five years. Since last 10 years, there are many funds from Inception as well,
they have good returns and in the last one or two years, those companies have launched more funds, their
returns are 35%, 40% and some funds have given returns of 50%. This fund
performance has been past It tells you about the future, what will be there in the future depends
on your fund sale and that particular fund, but it definitely tells
that you have got this type of returns in the past. Now let's talk about
other benefits and features of these five plans. Tax benefit in this,
on investing up to ₹ lakh in ATC, you get tax benefit in all these five policies.
You can give this receipt to your CA and if you
want to take the benefit of ATC, you can take it. And in these 500 plans, if you keep a premium of up to ₹ lakh
or less, then whatever maturity you get after that
will be tax free, no tax will be levied on it, but if you
invest through mutual fund or SIP, then you
have to pay long term capital gain tax there. Talking about surrender benefit, surrender benefit is available to you in only 500 policies.
After completion of five year lock-in period, you can surrender and
take the money. If you want then you can take grace period and free period, then
you will get the benefit of 30 days. After buying the policy, if you
do not like the policy for 30 days, you can take a free look at it and next year when the time for premium payment
comes and if you want to take a grace period of 30 days, then you can take it, during that time
also your insurance cover will start. Talking about revival period, since this
is in Uli policies, in this you will get revival period of nine years and not five years, that is,
if due to some reason you are not able to pay the premium, then for next 3 years
In this, you can continue the policy again by paying late fees etc. If medical test comes, then you
can get medical test done and continue the policy again. Will this plan be available to NRIs?
NRIs living in which country will get this plan? People living in which country
will not get it or will they get it at all? If an NRI wants to take the policy,
what will be the minimum income and education for them? If an Indian person
wants to purchase this policy, then what
should be his minimum ITR or salary income? What will be his education? If I am 12th pass, will I get this policy? If I
am a graduate, will I get this policy? Will a 5th pass person get this policy?
If it is available, then what will be the requirement of minimum income proof for this? If
you purchase this plan, how much money will go into your investment, how much
will go into your riders, how much will go into your insurance? I have not written all this here,
but you can know by consulting the number given below 0940 3412. You
can know all the benefits and features. If you liked the video, then before leaving I would like to thank the channel
Anil. Ra like, share and subscribe thank you so much Jai
Hind B